Now, when we made a merge, do we still need a fix branch.
I remind you that we only made it for the sake of the changes we've implemented inside it,
so that while they are a work in progress, we keep them separated from our main branch "master".
But once its done and merged with the master then, as they say "The moor has done his duty, the moor can go"
We dont need the fix any more, why do we keep another link to the same commit? Lets remove it.
Ветка fix больше не нужна - зачем нам еще одна ссылка на тот же коммит? Давайте ее удалим.
To remove a branch we can use the following command: "git branch -d fix"
Done. As you see, this command will only delete the "fix" link, the commits themselfs will remain in Git.
So, instead of two branches we only have one now. As you can see its all very simple.
Albeit theres one more thing: this command will perform a deletion only if the branch is merged with the current one.
Like in our case fix was merged with master.
It has not commits of its own, therefore the deletion was successful.
But if we try to delete the feature branch...
You see, an error.
The point is that deleting a branch is a dangerous thing.
Git has our back covered so we dont delete the branch that we might need still.
Indeed, lets imagine for a moment, that the feature branch was deleted. Snap and its gone.
In this case the commits, this one and this one, the ones that were only in the feature
are not a part of any of the current dev branches.
In this case only one branch has remained - master.
And here are commits that it has.
But not these ones.
Commits that are unavailable by any link are called unreachable. Git removes them from its database after a while.
If thats what we really want -
the feature branch is useless and we want to remove it and throw away the commits that we made for it only
then "git branch -D" will do this.
I also want to note, that in any way this command only removes the link.
The unreachable commits will be stored in a Git's database for some time.
Therefore if the deletion was just done, the image is the following.
If it appeared that the branch is still needed, then we can cancel the deletion.
Actually "cancel" is not exactly right here.
One can create a new branch with the same name,
that points to the same commit as the deleted one. I mean to this identifier.
Thats it, the feature is back again.